hello and welcome to weekend investing
daily bites we're shooting episode 291
and today we are going to have the ask
weekend investing round 29. so we do
these q a sessions
every now and then especially towards
the end of the week several times
in a quarter
and we try to answer any questions
related to strategies markets small case
operations and so on so forth so so far
we have addressed ah upwards of 500
queries unique queries and these queries
are available as a q a bank
and I'll show you where you can refer to
these all these are also YouTube videos
uh with links to each question so you
can very quickly search
for a particular query or a subject
within the weekend investing Hub but
first a look at the market so markets
opened lower
on the back of an extremely weak session
in the U.S markets but came back very
strongly uh
after the open itself and closed at 1.6
percent higher for the day
despite giving up some gains from the
top so it had almost reached two percent
um from previous closing and of course
the leading sector today was banking so
PSU Banks as well as private Banks led
the rally Metals Commodities energy
stocks and real estate also followed
suit it fmcg and Pharma were the least
gainers the defensive sectors but it was
very heartening to see that it sector
also rallied 0.6 percent despite a near
three percent crack on the NASDAQ so
with that
gain IIT and Pharma actually have gained
in the last one week of course all other
sectors are still in the red for the
week but nevertheless a good comeback it
could be a dead cat bounce we don't know
how the next week
or the periods will
will go from here but my sense is that
maybe
we may have a sideways or a you know
challenging environment for October
and maybe after Diwali uh you know
goddess Lakshmi will bless us all and we
will go up from there on
nifty 50
up 1.6 percent cnx 200 up 1.58 percent
and cnx 500 small cap index mid and
small cap index all up about one and a
half percent Nifty next 50 up only about
one percent
within the weekend investing uh small
cases
Mi 20 up two percent Mi 50 of 1.76
percent Mi 25 1.7 percent fantastic
performance from many of these only
laguards today to some extent were Mi a
t h m i a t h two and uh India top 10
also to some extent other than that all
other strategies did well and
in line with the underlying
markets today's heat map
was largely green although there were
pockets of red so cold India lost some
ground Britannia lost some ground Asian
paints has been losing for the last
couple of days Shri cement is on 1.1
percent
but the top gainers HDFC Bank Reliance
Bajaj Finance Bajaj finserv ICICI Bank
kotak bank indusind bank Titan maruti
bhart theater large winner jsw steel
Tata steel power grid all these were
good winners of two percent plus and
there were several stocks from zero to
two percent as well but fmcg as I said
uh was a bit lackluster today
top gainers adani green energy up 12.8
percent after total gas said that they
may prune some steak
that caused some flutters yesterday in
the afternoon and today morning but this
has come back very very strongly
um to close near 2260 India cements is
selling some unit and that is also up
nine and a half percent strides Pharma
which was down yesterday is up 7.7
percent
has been going up relentlessly up seven
in the top losers igl Gujarat
mahanagar gas
Sun Pharma Advanced research
and adani Transmissions were the ones
losing between three and a half to five
and a half percent some of these moves
are also due to the reshuffling of the
indices I I tweeted yesterday about the
several
stocks that are moving out of cnx 200 or
moving out of the
Nifty next 50 and some of these are due
to these moves of money coming in and
money going out
so so far in the weekend investing
rounds we have done 28 rounds all the
previous rounds are available in the
description link below you can go
through each of these videos
uh
567 questions have been answered pretty
much we've answered
all kinds and probably all the queries
that we have but we still get some more
queries so we keep answering all the
unique queries that we get so we'll
start with question 568 from Mr shravan
Kumar
he says previously
don't know till when but the recommended
size of ath and all cap was 5 to 15
lakhs but now I see all small cases are
5 lakhs to 30 lakhs how 30 lakhs makes
sense with respect to the market order
driven small cases as opposed to the 15
lakh previously so what we have done we
would we've increased the recommended
size for most strategies this has been
done after careful studies of the
slippage that we have seen and we have
studied in the last many months and we
feel confident that larger Capital can
be accommodated within the same
subscription costs thus lowering the
expense ratio for many of the users so
from that perspective it should be a
welcome step by most users who have been
wanting to you know have more Capital
run these strategies
uh the next one is again from Mr sravan
back in the past you have
once demoed that ath and all cap are the
best combination for raw Med I would
request people to please spell check
when they send the questions it becomes
very difficult uh romant ratio and all
does venturing into Mi top 10 makes
sense to someone who is having a so
we'll
I think we've done a romant ratio with
Mi top 10 against every strategy but if
we haven't covered this particular
combination please send us a mail and we
will uh we will respond to you on that
also we will very soon release
uh I think within the next 15 days
a website where you will be able to do
this automatically and see combined
results so I I am very very much looking
forward to that uh very very soon
uh the next question is
question 570
from
Ray Park
Chandra I hope I got your name right
I'm invested in nnf10
but my investment is below the
recommended capital I would like to take
Evergreen as it covers top 200 stocks
which are already covered in nnf10 and
top 10 it will bring my expense ratio
down can you please share thoughts on
the same so the Dynamics of nnf10 and
top 10 are very different from Evergreen
Evergreen is a very I would say uh
conservative play versus nnf10 and top
10 yes it will cover more stocks and it
will probably
bring your expense ratio down as well
but the Dynamics of the returns is very
different so I would like you to go
through the past results and then make
the decision uh there is nothing wrong
in in in the
current combination or the new one that
you may have I mean I think a lot of
people are
putting too much emphasis on expense
ratios Etc you must see it in context of
the returns that are expected if you go
to a strategy where the returns are
lower you even with a lower expense
ratio your net outcome may still be
lower
so have that in mind when you when you
look at any alternate strategy with
different expense ratios
next one is from Vivek how much time
period should be enough for coming to a
minimum amount required for specific
strategies for keeping expense ratio to
be minimum if you are doing manual
increments instead of say example all
cap has 5 to 30 lakh recommended amount
how many months per year
so I think I cannot prescribe any time
period
for uh coming up to the recommended
strategy I mean if you like I would like
you to start at 30 lakhs from day one
but uh it all depends upon what is your
Capital flow available and of course as
a
as a conservative strategy you should
spread it out over one or two years if
you have let's say you I mean you won a
lottery and you want to put in a lot of
lump sum I would still say bring it in
over a period of time and not
immediately but
again as I said in the previous question
don't give too much importance to the
expense ratio especially for first year
because you are in for the long term I
hope uh and not for six months or 12
months I mean if you're looking at five
years ten years type of a Runway then
one year of some additional expense
ratio is not going to you know kill the
returns for you so that's my sort of two
cents on this there's no real one you
know right or good answer for this
next one is from Mr punjan when Market
s fall value investing says buy the dip
will it apply to momentum investing as
well so
we we
don't really call
you know when you should add Capital
that is your choice
but you should bring in regular capital
is what I would prefer you know in some
ship or invest more fashion
and even when markets fall if you are
adding to a momentum portfolio it will
allocate either to cash or to you know
the most defensive stock so there's
nothing wrong in that
uh but uh yeah I mean this is definitely
not value investing what we do uh the
next part of the question is doing sip
always in any Market condition but like
to know what can we do in Market Falls
in terms of momentum investing
so momentum investing as I said nothing
specific
needs to be done
different from you know accumulating
Capital the idea is that you keep doing
sips in any type of market so that your
money gets accumulated and you don't
have to time the market when the market
takes off because it will do that
without informing us and only after you
know the first leg of the large move has
happened will we realize that oh yeah we
stopped we started in a bull market like
for instance today's move of two percent
I mean we don't know whether this is a
dead cat bounce or it's the start of
something bigger and nobody will know so
uh the whole idea of
this two minute investing per week is to
you know not focus too much on the
market and allow the system to take care
of it while we concentrate on you know
our life outside the market so that is
the sort of underlying principle
uh Teja has the next one very
interesting question any update on
loyalty discount programs thank you for
this question because we have been
relentlessly following this up with the
small case uh team and they have been
promising us that we will get this uh
definitely this financial year but I'm
hoping before uh before the calendar
year but it is somewhere in there road
map of technical uh features to be added
to the platform so I remain hopeful it
is not something that will not be done
it will get done but date is something
that is not in my head
next question
574 is from Arjun is market cap or
momentum indicator
yes market cap is a momentum indicator
since it is directly
proportionate to the price and
price move can give you a momentum
indication can a portfolio be built
using market cap only I mean invest in
top 20 stocks of market cap regardless
of performance and rotate monthly what
are your suggestions on Saturday yes it
can be done please try it out and share
your results with us I mean if they are
very good we will start a new product
based on it but I think this is very
much what uh is is our index formations
also made of these even the Nifty will
you know capture the top market caps and
and try to bring those into Nifty
so so this is the basis of mostly uh how
things work in the momentum world
Narendra has the next one I am a
subscriber of ath and all cap I am in a
dilemma that where Whenever there will
be a connection in the market like the
present week whether we buy the dip or
we need to wait for the next week to buy
because I feel the next week there will
be some change in stalker will raise the
cash
so again
don't try to micro time the market or
the strategy if you are bringing in
capital and if this if the uh strategy
is in cash I mean you'll hold cash for
some time
and then whenever the strategy gets
deployed you will deploy the cache or
like for instance right now most
strategies are fully in in deployment
then you bring in the cache and if
there's a dip I mean we lose some ground
but whenever it will rise see again we
are not trying to time the market
because nobody really can unless you are
a really you know Smart Cookie who can
pick every bottom and and top uh we
can't do that so
I mean given that we have a Runway of
have had a Runway of six and a half
years of Real Performance to show you
this has happened several times markets
have fallen markets have risen covered
happened you know all kinds of dips have
have happened since 2016 where when we
are running this in publicly
and the strategy do take care of it uh
more or less sometimes yeah we may lag
sometimes we may lead
I think the the larger question is that
if we are doing much better than
inflation if we are doing better than
the Benchmark we should be happy without
comparing it with anybody else so that's
my sort of two cents on this
uh question another question from Mr
Arjun in India top 10 why only use nifty
50 stocks why not use top market cap
stock so the whole design of the India
top 10 is to choose stocks from the
Nifty that's why we will choose stocks
on the Nifty if Nifty does not choose a
high market cap stock for whatever
reason we will also not pick that
next one is from Mr psychat Banerjee
hope you are doing good thank you sir I
would request can you please do a daily
bite on small case investment parameters
especially money put in current
investment value and the diversion
between them for better understanding
the same so no need really to do a daily
bite I'll uh point you to uh several uh
presentations that we have made on on
these definitions and topics and I'll
end examples of calculations so please
drop in a mail and we'll be happy to
share those things with you you can also
go through the weekend investing Hub
library and you'll get those details
there so yeah we can do that anytime you
like well this is the end of the weekend
investing ask we can investing round
thank you so much for sending in all
your queries uh I hope we are able to
take most of the queries and satisfy the
queries that have come in in case not
please
send us your uh
queries by email
uh we are happy to you know take and and
address any query that you send we don't
want any of our users or any of our
followers on Twitter to remain uh in
ambiguity about any question that we can
answer
so please do send us all your queries
and do share these videos with your
friends and family and we will be taking
a break on daily bites for the next
couple of weeks so we'll see you uh more
towards mid of next month and till then
goodbye and have a
safe month ahead bye